Henry “Hank” Oyama Papers, 1945-2003(Bulk 1973-1980; 1991-2002)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series IV: Articles, 1967-20003
  - Why the Bilingual Education Amendments Deserve Support (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Yazguirre, R. (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Series V: Newsletters, 1947, 1972-2000
  This series contains the newsletters of various organizations that Hank Oyama was a member of or that were of interest to him as a bilingual educator.
  - AACHE Newsletter (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - The Arizona Report (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Brainwaves (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - La Cadena de Teatro Carmen (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - El Centro Cultural Noticias (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - El Congreso Nacional de Asuntos Colegiales, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Discover (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - EPIC Events (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - ERIC Information Bulletin (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - La Fiesta Santificada (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Innovation Abstracts (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - The Link (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - La Lona, El Centro Cultural Artists’ Newsletter (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - The Mission Bell (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Music Matters (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - NABE News (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - News from the Borderlands (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Pima Community College Alumni Association Newsletter (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Pima Community College District Bulletin (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Rotary Club of Tucson Newsletter (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Sister Cities (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - TABE (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - TuSerran (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - UA Hispanic Alumni Newsletter (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - La Voz de Aztlan, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 46)
- Series VI: Publications, 1943, 1945, 1947, 1968-2003
  The publications in this series are books, catalogs, and informational pamphlets published by organizations and individuals interested in the bilingual education movement.
  - Ballet Folklorico (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - The Bilingual Journal, Winter, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Centros de Asistencia y Servicios Tecnológicos (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - The Chicano Movement: Some Not Too Objective Observations by Abelardo B. Delgado (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Color and Learn: The Book of the Sun Tonatiuh = Colorea y Aprende: El Libro del Sol Orozco (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Community, Technical, and Junior College Journal, June/July 1989 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Earl Carroll Theatre Restaurant Hollywood (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Easy Tricks with Numbers (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Edificios Antiguos de Guadalajara (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Gates Millennium Scholars (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Guide of the Regional Museum of Guadalajara by José G. Zuno (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - The Heliograph (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - “Los Hombres de la Reforma”…y dieron su vida! (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - I Am a Doughboy (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Industrial Park, Obregon City, Sonora, Mexico (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Joel D. Valdez Main Library Dedication Ceremony (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - The Mexican-American and the United States by Charles J. and Patricia L. Bustamante (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - The Multilingual Educator (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - National Law Center for Inter-American Free Trade (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - NEA Research Bulletin, Vol. 46: 2, May 1968 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Report of a National Bilingual Bicultural Institute: A Relook at Tucson ’66 and Beyond (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Report of the Chicano Ad Hoc Special Interest Group, Stanford University (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Saint Cyril Parish (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - San Francisco Tours of Discovery (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Search for Opportunity (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Souvenir du Restaurant Antoine (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Tres Cosas Lindas Hay en la Vida (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Tucson Unified School District Compliance Procedures Manual for Bilingual Education, January 1994 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - The University of Arizona Foundation Report, Fall 2001 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Series VII: Addition of Papers, 1986-2005
  Addition to papers documenting Henry Oyama’s leading role in fundraising for scholarships for bilingual students through various organizations. The papers consist of scholarship requirements, meeting minutes, consultancy and financial reports, donor lists, scholarship backgrounds and event planning.
  - Amigos, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Amigos, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Amigos II, 2001-2002 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Amigos III, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Amigos IV, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Amigos IV, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Amigos V (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Gilbert Acosta (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Gilbert Acosta (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Gilbert Acosta (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Gilbert Acosta (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Jacinto Orozco (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Jacinto Orozco (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Jacinto Orozco (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Dave Kennon & Manuel Bedoya Scholarships (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - University of Phoenix (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - PCC/DC Bilingual Program & Tucson Hispanic Coalition (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - PCC Foundation Registers (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Tucson & PCC Bilingual Legacy (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Angel Hernandez (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Briefcase (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Tardeada, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Tardeada, 1998-2001 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Tardeada, 1998-2001 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Tardeada, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Tardeada, 2004-2005 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Consultancy Report (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Consultancy Report, 1993-1997 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Consultancy Report, 1997-2005 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Hispanic Student Endowment Fund (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Hispanic Student Endowment Fund (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Hispanic Student Endowment Fund, 1986-2001 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Hispanic Student Endowment Fund, 1986-2001 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Hispanic Student Endowment Fund (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Hispanic Student Endowment Fund (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Amigos/HSEF/Tardeada, 2004-2005 (Box 19, Folder 7)